<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MeelGroup on MeelGroup</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MeelGroup on MeelGroup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper on Sparse Hashing for Approximate Model counting accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://lics.siglog.org/lics20/&#34;&gt;LICS 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Authors: S. Akshay and Kuldeep S. Meel&lt;br&gt;One of the reviews: &#34;Rarely it is that there is a paper that proves a beautiful new theoretical result, explaining and simplifying previous work, and on top of that shows how it can be used to improve state-of-the-art practical algorithms. The paper &#34;Sparse hashing for scalable approximate model counting: theory and practice&#34; achieves exactly that.&#34;</title>
      <link>/news/10042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/10042020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://easychair.org/smart-program/LPAR23/&#34;&gt;LPAR-23&lt;/a&gt;. The paper formalizes Induction Models on N extending the classical work of Henkin. Authors: A Dileep, Kuldeep S. Meel and Ammar F. Sabili</title>
      <link>/news/08042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/08042020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Papers accepted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/cavconference/?fref=mentions&#34;&gt;Computer Aided Verification (CAV)&lt;/a&gt; 2020 conference.&lt;br&gt;1. The first paper proposes a new approach that combines sampling&#43;machine learning&#43;MaxSAT to achieve a significant progress in solving Boolean Functional Synthesis. Authors: Priyanka Golia, Subhajit Roy, and Kuldeep S. Meel&lt;br&gt;2. The second paper builds on our CNF-XOR solving paradigm (BIRD) and as a result, the new versions of ApproxMC and UniGen are faster than ever. Stay tuned for our releases. Authors: Mate Soos, Stephan Gocht, and Kuldeep S. Meel&lt;br&gt;3. The third paper proposes the first algorithm for approximate MUS counting. Authors: Jaroslav Bendik and Kuldeep S. Meel</title>
      <link>/news/06042020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/06042020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling-based approach for quantittive quantitative verification of Deep Neural Nets. We propose a new attack agnostic metric adversarial hardness to capture the model&amp;apos;s robustness: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.06864.pdf&#34;&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.06864.pdf&lt;/a&gt;  Authors: Teodora Baluta, Zheng Leong Chua, Kuldeep S. Meel and Prateek Saxena.</title>
      <link>/news/18022020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/18022020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexey Ignatiev, Joao Marques-Silva, Kuldeep S. Meel and Nina Narodytska give a tutorial at the Tutorial Forum in AAAI&amp;apos;20: &lt;a href=&#34;https://aaai.org/Conferences/AAAI-20/aaai20tutorials/&#34;&gt;Rigorous Verification and Explanation of ML Models&lt;/a&gt;.</title>
      <link>/news/08022020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/08022020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NPAQ</title>
      <link>/software/npaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/npaq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neural networks are increasingly employed in safety-critical domains. This has prompted interest in verifying or certifying logically encoded properties of neural networks. Prior work has largely focused on checking existential properties, wherein the goal is to check whether there exists any input that violates a given property of interest. However, neural network training is a stochastic process, and many questions arising in their analysis require probabilistic and quantitative reasoning, i.e., estimating how many inputs satisfy a given property. To this end, our paper proposes a novel and principled framework to quantitative verification of logical properties specified over neural networks. Our framework is the first to provide PAC-style soundness guarantees, in that its quantitative estimates are within a controllable and bounded error from the true count. We instantiate our algorithmic framework by building a prototype tool called NPAQ that enables checking rich properties over binarized neural networks. We show how emerging security analyses can utilize our framework in 3 applications: quantifying robustness to adversarial inputs, efficacy of trojan attacks, and fairness/bias of given neural networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~teodorab/papers/NPAQ.pdf&#34; title=&#34;CCS 2019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CCS 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Rules in Relaxed Logical Form</title>
      <link>/publication/ecai20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecai20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on classification rules in relaxed logical form is accepted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecai2020.eu&#34;&gt;ECAI-2020&lt;/a&gt;. Authors: Bishwamittra Ghosh, Dmitry Malioutov, and Kuldeep S. Meel</title>
      <link>/news/15012020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/15012020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A MaxSAT-based Framework for Group Testing</title>
      <link>/publication/aaai20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/aaai20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on Symmetry breaking and model counting is accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etaps.org/2020/tacas&#34;&gt;TACAS 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Authors: Wenxi Wang, Muhammad Usman, Alyas Almaawi, Kaiyuan Wang, Kuldeep S. Meel, and Sarfraz Khurshid</title>
      <link>/news/23122019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/23122019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Two of our group&amp;apos;s papers are accepted to accepted as poster presentations with a spotlight talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.starai.org/2020/&#34;&gt;StarAI 2020&lt;/a&gt; workshop in &lt;a href=&#34;https://aaai.org/Conferences/AAAI-20/&#34;&gt;AAAI 2020&lt;/a&gt;: Our AIES-19 &lt;a href=&#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/imli-ghosh.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on incremental classification rule learning and our CCS-19 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~teodorab/papers/NPAQ.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on quantiatative verification for binarized neural networks.</title>
      <link>/news/07122019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/07122019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrystalBall: SAT solving, Data Gathering, and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/crystallball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/crystallball/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/i&gt;Link to the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msoos.org/2019/06/crystalball-sat-solving-data-gathering-and-machine-learning/&#34;&gt;original post&lt;/a&gt; on CrystallBall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Alexis will be presenting our work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/cp19-dm.pdf&#34;&gt;unifying hashing-based approaches for discrete integration&lt;/a&gt;, and Bishwa will present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/irr-ghosh.pdf&#34;&lt;/a&gt; learning interpretable classifiers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cp2019.a4cp.org/&#34;&gt;CP2019&lt;/a&gt;.</title>
      <link>/news/30092019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/30092019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Embedding Symbolic Knowledge into Deep Networks </title>
      <link>/publication/neurips19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/neurips19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/aaai_2020/AAAI-CiampiconiL.690.pdf&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on  MaxSAT-based formulation for group testing is accepted in &lt;a href=&#34;https://aaai.org/Conferences/AAAI-20/&#34;&gt;AAAI 2020&lt;/a&gt;. Authors: Lorenzo Ciampiconi, Bishwamittra Ghosh, Jonathan Scarlett and Kuldeep S. Meel</title>
      <link>/news/11112019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/11112019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
