<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MeelGroup on MeelGroup</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MeelGroup on MeelGroup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title> Alexis will be presenting our work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/cp19-dm.pdf&#34;&gt;unifying hashing-based approaches for discrete integration&lt;/a&gt;, and Bishwa will present on &lt;a href=&#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/irr-ghosh.pdf&#34;&lt;/a&gt; learning interpretable classifiers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cp2019.a4cp.org/&#34;&gt;CP2019&lt;/a&gt;.</title>
      <link>/news/30092019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/30092019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Paper on &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.01161&#34;&gt;embedding symbolic knowledge into Neural Networks&lt;/a&gt; is accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://nips.cc/&#34;&gt;NeurIPS 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&#34; Authors: Yaqi Xie, Ziwei Xu, Mohan S. Kankanhalli, Kuldeep S. Meel, Harold Soh</title>
      <link>/news/01092019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/01092019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Quantitative Verification of Neural Networks And its Security Applications  </title>
      <link>/publication/ccs19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ccs19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We presented three papers at IJCAI-19. 1) The first paper explores the [phase transition behavior of conjunction of cardinality and XOR constraints](https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/ijcai19pjm.pdf). 2) The second paper describes a radically new approach to exact counting wherein we compute estimates that are [probabilistically exact](https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/ijcai19srsm.pdf)! 3) The third one is our invited paper on [#DNF](https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/ijcai19msv.pdf).</title>
      <link>/news/13082019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/13082019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have released the source code of [GANAK](https://github.com/meelgroup/ganak).</title>
      <link>/news/12082019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/12082019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1906.10395&#34;&gt;NPAQ framework &lt;/a&gt;focused on providing PAC guarantees for verification of Neural Networks is accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sigsac.org/ccs/CCS2019/&#34;&gt;CCS-19&lt;/a&gt; Quoting reviewer: “This work is pioneering a new technique to solve an incredibly challenging problem, and it shows that smaller problem can be solved. I can live with that, future work can improve computational efficiency.&#34; Authors: Teodora Baluta, Shiqi Shen, Shweta Shinde, Kuldeep S. Meel, Prateek Saxena</title>
      <link>/news/30072019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/30072019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Hashing-based Algorithms for Discrete Integration  </title>
      <link>/publication/cp19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cp19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ApproxMC</title>
      <link>/software/approxmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/approxmc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ApproxMC is a hashing-based algorithm for approximate discrete integration over finite domains and provides ($\epsilon$,$\delta$) guarantees. This implementation handles the case when the function is implicitely defined by SAT formula. To the best of our knowledge, the current implementation has the best runtime performance among approximate counting algorithms. We are actively improving algorithm as well as implementation and would love to hear your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/ijcai16_counting.pdf&#34; title=&#34;IJCAI 2016&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IJCAI 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/constraints16.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Constraints 2016&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Constraints 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/CP2013.pdf&#34; title=&#34;CP 2013&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CP 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrystalBall</title>
      <link>/software/crystalball/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/crystalball/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boolean satisfiability is a fundamental problem in computerscience with a wide range of applications including planning, configurationmanagement, design and verification of software/hardware systems. Modern SAT solvers achieve scalability and ro-bustness with sophisticated heuristics that are challenging to understandand explain. We propose to view modern conflict-driven clause learning (CDCL) solvers as a composition of classifiers and regressors for different tasks such as branching, clause memory management, and restarting. The current version of CrystalBall focuses on deriving a classifier to keep or throw away a learned clause. In a departure from recent machine learning based techniques, CrystalBall employs supervised learning anduses extensive, multi-gigabyte data extracted from runs of a single SAT solver to perform predictive analytics. Read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msoos.org/2019/06/crystalball-sat-solving-data-gathering-and-machine-learning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msoos.org/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/sat19-skm.pdf&#34; title=&#34;SAT 2019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SAT 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UniGen</title>
      <link>/software/unigen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/unigen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UniGen is a hashing-based algorithm to generate uniform samples subject to given set of constraints. The primary application of UniGen is in random stimuli generation for hardware and software verification. The current version of the tool has been developed over the years and is parallelizable without losing theoretical guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/Tacas15.pdf&#34; title=&#34;TACAS 2015&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TACAS 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/DAC2014.pdf&#34; title=&#34;DAC 2014&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DAC 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/cav13.pdf&#34; title=&#34;CAV 2013&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CAV 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Interpretable Classification Rules in Relaxed Logical Form </title>
      <link>/publication/ijcai19_irr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ijcai19_irr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on &lt;a href= &#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/irr-ghosh.pdf&#34;&gt;interpretable rules expressed as relaxed-CNF&lt;/a&gt; is accepted at IJCAI workshop on XAI (Explainable Artificial Intelligence) and DSO (Data Science meets Optimization), 2019. Authors: Bishwamittra Ghosh, Dmitry Malioutov, Kuldeep S. Meel.</title>
      <link>/news/23062019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/23062019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GANAK</title>
      <link>/software/ganak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/software/ganak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given a Boolean formula $F$, the problem of  model counting, also referred to as #SAT, seeks to compute the number of solutions of $F$. Model counting is a fundamental problem with a wide variety of applications ranging from planning, quantified information flow to probabilistic reasoning and the like. The modern #SAT solvers tend to be either based on static decomposition, dynamic decomposition, or a hybrid of the two. Despite dynamic decomposition based #SAT solvers sharing much of their architecture with SAT solvers, the core design and heuristics of dynamic decomposition-based #SAT solvers has remained constant for over a decade. In this paper, we revisit the architecture of the state-of-the-art dynamic decomposition-based #SAT tool, sharpSAT, and demonstrate that by introducing a new notion of probabilistic component caching and the usage of universal hashing for exact model counting along with the development of several new heuristics can lead to significant performance improvement over state-of-the-art model-counters. In particular, we develop GANAK, a new scalable probabilistic exact model counter that outperforms state-of-the-art exact and approximate model counters sharpSAT and ApproxMC3 respectively, both in terms of PAR-2 score and the number of instances solved. Furthermore, in our experiments, the model count returned by GANAK was equal to the exact model count for all the benchmarks. Finally, we observe that recently proposed preprocessing techniques for model counting benefit exact model counters while hurting the performance of approximate model counters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Papers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/ijcai19srsm.pdf&#34; title=&#34;IJCAI 2019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IJCAI 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Reliability Estimation in Theory and Practice </title>
      <link>/publication/ress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ress/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GANAK: A Scalable Probabilistic Exact Model Counter</title>
      <link>/publication/ijcai19_ganak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ijcai19_ganak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
