<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on MeelGroup</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on MeelGroup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description> Meel Group Welcome to the Meel Group&amp;rsquo;s web page. We are situated at National University of Singapore.
Interests
 Artificial Intelligence  Constrained Sampling and Counting  Knowledge Representation and Reasoning  Formal Methods  Interpretable Models  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/home/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/research/</guid>
      <description>Overview Broadly, our research group is focused on the development of a rigorous mathematical framework for  provably verified, correct-by-construction, explainable probabilistic reasoning systems  building on recent breakthroughs in formal methods and symbolic reasoning; and deployment of our algorithmic framework in the real world including applications in reliability estimation of critical infrastructure and computational sustainabilit.yfa We seek to develop formal methods for AI techniques and also employ advances in AI techniques for development of formal method algorithmic and system frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>/home/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/news/</guid>
      <description>20 June 2018 I will be at IJCAI from July 12 – July 19 and at Leiden University on July 20. I will be co-presenting tutorial with Supratik Chakraborty at IJCAI on July 13.
# -- 15 May 2019  Kuldeep recieved notification of the award ofNRF Fellowship for AI  for the project: Provably Verified and Explainable Probabilistic Reasoning. 9 May 2019 Two papers accepted to IJCAI.The first paper explores the phase transition behavior of conjunction of cardinality and XOR constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>/home/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/people/</guid>
      <description>Faculty Kuldeep Meel
PhD Students  body .column { float: left; width: 33.33%; padding: 5px; }
/* Clear floats after image containers */ .row::after { content: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;; clear: both; display: table; }    Yash Pote   Priyanka Golia   Bishwamittra Ghosh    Suwei    Masters Students   .column { float: left; width: 33.33%; padding: 5px; }
/* Clear floats after image containers */ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description>Kuldeep S. Meel
Assistant Professor
Computer Science Department, School of Computing
National University of Singapore
Please consult Kuldeep&amp;rsquo;s calendar  before suggesting a meeting time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openings</title>
      <link>/home/openings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/openings/</guid>
      <description>We are always looking for highly motivated Ph.D. students, research assistants and summer internship for exceptional undergraduate interns in our group. We work at the intersection of algorithmic design and systems; therefore, an ideal candidate should have deeper expertise in one area and willingness to learn the other. A strong background in statistics, algorithms/formal methods and prior experience in coding is crucial to make a significant contribution to our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>