<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on MeelGroup</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on MeelGroup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on &lt;a href= &#34;https://bishwamittra.github.io/publication/irr-ghosh.pdf&#34;&gt;interpretable rules expressed as relaxed-CNF&lt;/a&gt; is accepted at IJCAI workshop on XAI (Explainable Artificial Intelligence) and DSO (Data Science meets Optimization), 2019. Authors: Bishwamittra Ghosh, Dmitry Malioutov, Kuldeep S. Meel.</title>
      <link>/news/23062019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/23062019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuldeep recieved notification of the award of &lt;a href= &#34;https://www.nrf.gov.sg/funding-grants/nrf-fellowship-for-artificial-intelligence&#34;&gt; NRF Fellowship for AI &lt;/a&gt; for the project: Provably Verified and Explainable Probabilistic Reasoning.</title>
      <link>/news/15052019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/15052019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted to IJCAI.The first paper explores the phase transition behavior of conjunction of cardinality and XOR constraints. Authors: Yash Pote, Saurabh Joshi, Kuldeep Meel.&lt;br&gt; The second paper describes a radically new approach to exact counting wherein we compute estimates that are probabilistically exact! Authors: Shubham Sharma, Kuldeep Meel. Combined with our invited paper on &lt;a href= &#34;https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~meel/Papers/CP2018msv.pdf&#34;&gt; #DNF &lt;/a&gt;, this makes 3 papers that we will be presenting at IJCAI.</title>
      <link>/news/09052019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/09052019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted to SAT 2019. The first paper introduces the first version of CrystalBall, a framework intended to allow gazing into the black box of SAT solving. Authors: Kuldeep, Mate Soos, Raghav Kulkarni.&lt;br&gt; The second paper discusses how model counting can be used to analyze explanations provided by tools such as ANCHOR. Authors: Kuldeep, Nina Narodytska, Aditya Shrotri, Alexey Ignatiev, and Joao Marques Silva.</title>
      <link>/news/22042019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/22042019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuldeep  is appointed Visiting Assistant Professor in the  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cse.iitb.ac.in/&#34;&gt;Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/a&gt;  at IIT Bombay.</title>
      <link>/news/11022019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/11022019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper on network reliability is accepted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icasp13.snu.ac.kr/&#34;&gt;The 13th International Conference on Applications of Statistics and Probability in Civil Engineering &lt;/a&gt; Authors: Roger Paredes, Leonardo Duenas-Osorio, Kuldeep S. Meel, and Moshe Y. Vardi.</title>
      <link>/news/02022019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/02022019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper on weighted and projected sampling is accepted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://conf.researchr.org/track/etaps-2019/tacas-2019-papers&#34;&gt;TACAS 2019&lt;/a&gt;. Authors: Shubham Sharma, Rahul Gupta, Subhajit Roy and Kuldeep S. Meel.</title>
      <link>/news/26012019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/26012019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>